# ROBERT **BISHOP** IR FULL-STACK **DEVELOPER**

**\** 804.869.2541

**♀** Las Vegas, NV

in www.linkedin.com/in/robertbishop-3837b61

I am an enthusiastic, selfdisciplined and motivated worker. I have demonstrated an ability to work on teams and with management, as well as learn new skills and work remotely. I would like to find a work environment where I can continue to learn from others while becoming a valuable member of a team. My experience at PunchCode has opened a world of excitement and opportunity, my hope is that I can continue to make consistent progress towards my goal of becoming a seasoned developer.

## Skills

#### **TECHNOLOGY EXPERIENCE**

CSS/Sass HTMI

**JavaScript** 

react.js

redux

node.js express

socket.io

mySQL

## **Education**

PunchCode Certificate

Virginia Commonwealth University B.A. Philosophy 2003

Sept. 1998 to May 2003

Remote - Las Vegas, NV

Jan. 2020 to Apr. 2020

# **Employment History**

#### Technology Credit Union

Remote Universal Contact Center Specialist

Jan. 2019 to Dec. 2019 After leaving San Jose, CA to move to Las Vegas, NV, my employer TechCU offered me the opportunity to pilot a new remote role at the Credit Union. TechCU was looking for the right employee candidate to test this program due to the discipline required and security concerns of working in real time with customer banking details from home. The pilot included cooperation with myself, IT, the Executive Team, the AVP and VP of the Contact Center in order to make this project a success. We were successful in that I was a fully functional Contact Center Specialist for a CA Credit Union while living full-time in Las Vegas for the entire term of the 12 month trial. Many employees did not know I was remote and none of our customers knew. The Executive Team was able to approve the program with our Board of Directors and implement the remote model across several departments in 2019 making this remote agent pilot program a success. My specific responsibilities included all banking verification and full account services for our

#### Business Development / Auto Loan Channel

San Jose, CA Feb. 2016 to Dec. 2018

My role in Business Development for TechCU's auto loan channel was to improve, expand and maintain our working relationships with the franchise auto dealers in the San Jose Region. I made regular in person dealer account calls in order to promote TechCU products as well as resolve in process loan application issues for our customers. To ensure a smooth process for our customers, I collaborated with dealer contacts, TechCU's banking staff, and the Underwriting Department.

#### Sr Relationship Banker

Dublin, CA Mar. 2014 to Jan. 2016

Sr Relationship Banker responsibilities included all in branch customer account services as well as currency inventory management. Staff was expected to keep audit logs and maintain dual control on currency movements in the vault. In addition to account services, Branch staff exercised discretion on customer accounts and strict compliance with all banking regulations. Our Branch was run by a small team and cooperation was key to our success.

#### Carnival Cruise Lines

Musician

customers.

**Onboard Cruise Ships** June 2008 to Aug. 2012

A life long passion of mine is playing music. In 2008, I followed my passion of playing drums into a lifestyle by taking a position as an onboard musician on cruise ships. Living on ships and playing music was a very unique and enjoyable experience in my life, affording me an opportunity to travel to many places and meet my wife along the

### Member Mortgage Solutions

Mortgage Loan Officer

Richmond, VA May 2006 to May 2008

In addition to facilitating the loan process for customers purchasing homes, mortgage loan officer develops accounts with lead sources such as Credit Unions and Realtors. My time was split between business development and customer application duties while working at Member Mortgage Solutions. I left the job due to the 2008 mortgage crisis, there were no home loans available and no customers purchasing at that time.

## **Videos for Capstone Project and Bio Introduction**

My capstone project for the PunchCode curriculum is called Jurn(ease). It is a vacation planning site aimed at making the planning process cooperative between groups of travelers and relieving the stress of that process.

Jurn(ease) Video Short Presentation

Jurn(ease) Video Project Demonstration

Introduction Video Bio for Robert Bishop

#### Playing Music

I have played music most of my life, starting in middle school continuing through high school and college. I have been fortunate enough to work as a full-time professional as well as a local performer. I have also had the pleasure of teaching private lessons to younger students when my schedule allows.